Ben Young Mwanzia

Nairobi, Kenya

9 bynmz.github.io

github.com/bynmz

■ bynmwz@gmail.com **in** linkedin.com/in/bynmz

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with over 7 years of experience specializing in; automotive, mobile, web and computer graphics software development. Throughout my career I have demonstrated strong problem-solving skills, meticulous attention to detail, and effective teamwork. My ability to estimate project timelines accurately allows me to consistently deliver solutions within the desired time-frame.

EXPERIENCE

Nile Origin Studios Ltd. **Founding Engineer**

Nairobi, Kenya January 2022 - Present

The organization was founded with a dual focus; technical writing and the development of proprietary tools to enhance graphics technology and streamline workflows for engines such as Unity and Unreal Engine 5. We emphasize pragmatic steps and deliver iterative improvements within the Agile framework. In 2023, we developed several powerful internal tools, including custom optimization and performance-monitoring solutions, specifically designed to improve the efficiency of existing game engines and development workflows. .

- Developed data pipelines and analytics solutions to collect real-time telemetry and performance data from various game engines, helping developers make data-driven optimizations to their workflows and asset pipelines.
- Built custom tooling that integrates with existing engines (Unity and Unreal), allowing teams to profile assets, optimize shader performance, and manage resources more effectively. These tools improved iteration speed and performance tuning for large, complex projects.
- Collaborated with fellow application developers to conduct architecture reviews and implement automation workflows, including automated testing and Agile methodologies, across cross-functional teams.
- Mentored new hires and created a standard process for interviewing and on-boarding within our team
- · Created and led the Developer Experience employee interest group in the organization, which aimed to increase software engineering productivity and cohesion through the company through collaboration, knowledge sharing, and establishment of new conventions

Roam Electric Ltd. Senior Software Engineer

Nairobi, Kenya May 2021 - October 2023

Formerly Opibus, the organization underwent re-branding to Roam Electric in 2021. Roam Electric is an e-mobility manufacturing and development company. It provides EV powertrain, electric motorcycles, buses, power generation systems, and charging infrastructures. In the software engineering department I was integral to the success of several of the software products which Included the EV HMI (Godot/ 3D), infotainment systems and asset management (GIS) mobile and web apps for Roam EV owners.

- I initiated and executed the setup of data pipelines to capture and integrate EV asset telemetry data into the BigQuery (GCP) data warehouse. This significantly increased data visibility and enhanced data driven decision-making for the organization.
- Collaborated with a team of developers on maintaining and upgrading the EV HMI UX/UI using Godot, and updates to the system firmware (C/C++) by implementing data sending features over MQTT. This effort led to a 50% productivity increase for electric vehicle (EV) maintenance teams.
- Designed and developed a fleet and charging session management mobile application in react native, optimizing operations for EV owners.
- Updated automated deploy flows to incorporate unit and integration testing using Google Compute Engine and Google Cloud Build.

Circle Digital is a full service digital marketing agency based in Nairobi, Kenya and London. During my time at the organization I played an integral part in the delivery of software products that included e-commerce, online portals for educational institutions and online directories for a variety of clients which include renown talent agencies.

- Led the development of Angular and Node.js-based clients including roadmapping and drafting technical specifications
- · Worked in a team of six engineers; collaborated with iOS, and Android teams on cross-platform architectural decisions
- Core contributor to a customized fork of an open-source WebRTC framework, added features that enabled efficient data transfer across platforms (Node.js, Node Native Modules)
- Ensured smooth data flow and reliable sync of data between iOS, Android, and web clients by implementing missing data channels, pinpointing packet queue bottlenecks, and debugging across multiple server- and client-side components (WebRTC, WebSockets, some Objective-C++)
- Assisted in screening, interviewing, hiring, and on-boarding of new team members

EDUCATION

United States International University - Africa Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Information & Computer Science Nairobi, Kenya May 2012 - September 2016

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE & ACTIVITIES

Lions Sight-first Eye Hospital Loresho - Data entry

2015 - 2016

More projects, activities, and writing available at bynmz.github.io